# Michael Appleton

Edmonds, WA 98026 tkphone4628@gmail.com 4253661411

I was first employed at 16 and then after that was continually hired by friends that managed places and enjoyed my time with them. I am excited to interview for my first time since I was 16. I have 12 years of customer service experience, answering phones, solving problems for the customers, taking orders, going on lengthy well informed tangents to help the customer on the other end of the phone. 7 years of handling money at a register wish customers face to face. I have worked in a fast paced kitchen where you have many things to multi task so I am good at having many irons in the fire and am proficient in POS systems. I also can type pretty fast am computer savvy and I am a fast learner. I pride myself on spotting what is wrong and trying to fix that including my own ability to do the job. I like to be very productive and am very loyal. Helping teammates succeed is very important to me. I am in good shape and can stay on my feet or bend all day including lifting heavy things constantly. I have great memory for where product goes and have always used that to the company I work fors advantage. I am also very good at math. Mostly, I am looking to find a job where the people in charge want everyone to succeed and care about the standards they create. I enjoy structure and a working environment that trains what they preach and practices what they preach. Thank you for your time.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

## Work Experience

## Warehouse Worker/Forklift Operator

Wesco Group Inc. - Mountlake Terrace, WA June 2014 to April 2019

Pulled orders. Loaded orders into trucks. Signed for goods. Operated forklifts. Worked in a fast paced very physical job with many co workers. First aid and CPR certified. Forklift and hazmat shipping certified. Was lifting over 50 pounds and on feet and moving for the entire work day. Ascended and descended ladders with goods. Answered phone calls with varieties of problems and did my best to solve them or find an appropriate co worker. I enjoyed the largeness of the scale of shipping and receiving ,the technical work of filling shelves pulling orders and precision forklift driving. Filled out purchase orders, requested credits from manufacturers, counted inventory of the warehouse many times. Helped manage other employees when the manager was out for 3 years of working there. Was a key holder.

#### Pizza Maker/Manager

Prime Pizza - Mountlake Terrace, WA August 2007 to June 2014

This was my first job. Company was sold so I had to find a new job. Owned by Jung Yoon Oh. Answered phones, processed orders on a pos, handled customers face to face. Served customers in our front of house and worked the register. It was a fast paced kitchen with many multi tasking opportunities. I can make a cheese pizza in 50 seconds. I handled money with customers face to face and helped the family business feel tight knit. I enjoyed making high quality food and serving customers with high quality attitude and patience. We also had upsell items to lean customers to and help the bottom line

while also being informative and fair. I was the manager there for the last 5 years or so of working there. I enjoyed over seeing and fixing anything going wrong planning and communicating with the owner. Working in the same neighborhood I grew up in was incredibly rewarding and I truly enjoyed the regular customers. We worked next to a large 500+ degree large pizza oven and I was on my feet for the shifts. I hand made from scratch pizza dough,sauce and cooked many things in deep fryers, flat top grills and broiler. Quality standards in food and customer service were always paramount.

## **Inventory Control Specialist**

PICS Inventory Specialists - Edmonds, WA February 2012 to February 2013

I worked for Phyle Inventory Control Specialists for a around a year. At the time my friend got me into training and I learned how to us their scanner and computers. I have managed my own teams to inventory pharmacies and other locations. I enjoyed the math and mapping my fingers over the computer to quickly count goods. We were in stores while they were open for the most part so being professional yet accommodating and getting your job done at the same time was a must. It was common the answer questions about where something would be in the store even though you were not an employee but most of the stores we frequented and it became easy to remember having counted the goods. Counting inventory I could average some very high numbers including millions per day and my profit margin as an employee was 99.9%. Due to it being how much you make and how much you counted. Their training was fantastic and I enjoyed the structure and order.

#### Education

Mountlake Terrace High School - Mountlake Terrace, WA September 2005 to June 2009

## High school or equivalent

#### Skills

Inventory Control (5 years), shipping, Customer Service (10+ years), Pallet Jack, Excel, Shipping And Receiving (4 years), Microsoft Word, Forklift Operator (4 years), Cashier (7 years), Answering Phones (10+ years), POS (7 years)

## Certifications/Licenses

## **Certified Forklift Operator**

#### First Aid CPR AED

July 2018 to July 2020

Got first aid CPR and aed certified with the red cross at the Lynnwood convention center

#### Additional Information

Character References:

Victoria Glenn Owner of Victoria's Bridal 425 248 1156

Brett Cederberg Owner of Gemini Tile and Marble 206 335 8861

Julia Barbee Manager at Hairmasters 206 573 8822

Jung Yoon Oh Former owner of Prime Pizza